Register of the Victor Gilinsky Papers, 1943-1984
Hoover Institution Archives
Victor Gilinsky Papers,
1943-1984
82091
Gilinsky, Victor, 1934-
632 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 3 envelopes, 12 slides (265.3 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Reports, memoranda, transcripts of hearings and telephone conversations, correspondence, and printed matter, relating to nuclear power plants, mainly in the United States, including issues of domestic and international licensing, fuel cycle and waste management, emergency planning, safety problems, and the Three Mile Island nuclear accident.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research. Collection stored off site; a minimum of two days notice is required for use. Boxes may be requested through Stanford's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1982.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
United States. Nuclear Regulatory Commission; Nuclear energy--United States; Nuclear energy; Three Mile Island Nuclear Power Plant (Pa.); United States--Politics and government
Biographical Note
1934, May 28 Born, Warsaw, Poland
1961-1971 Physicist, Rand Corporation, Santa Monica, California
1971-1973 Assistant Director, Policy and Program Review, Atomic Energy Commission (AEC)
1973-1975 Head, Department of Physical Science, Rand Corporation, Santa Monica, California
1975-1984 Member, United States Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC)
Scope and Content
This collection covers the period of Dr. Victor Gilinsky's service on the United States Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) from 1975 to 1984. The Energy Reorganization Act of 1974 abolished the Atomic Energy Commission (AEC), assigning its licensing and regulatory functions to the NRC; the promotional aspects were transferred to the Energy Research and Development Agency (ERDA). In 1977 the Department of Energy (DOE) was established to co-ordinate federal energy research and development programs. Dr. Gilinsky was appointed to the NRC by President Gerald Ford in 1975, and reappointed by President Jimmy Carter in 1979.
Dr. Gilinsky's special areas of interest included the conflict between nuclear non-proliferation goals and the role of the United States as a major nuclear provider. He often stressed that licensing delays resulted as much from the lack of design standardization and variable levels of utility management expertise as from regulatory caution or deliberate obstructionism. Dr. Gilinsky's tenure was controversial at times because he expressed dissenting opinions in the public media and to Congressional oversight committees. Within this collection, these opinions are found both in the SPEECHES AND WRITINGS FILE, and in other series under relevant subject headings.
Areas of concentration of materials include the 1979 accident at Three Mile Island (154 boxes), the Diablo Canyon power plant (48 boxes), fuel cycle and waste management issues (35 boxes), and the materials generated by the NRC Office of the Secretary (SECY Papers), described below (107 boxes).
In some cases, brief notations indicate major issues, but the absence of such notation does not indicate lack of significance. The notes are not comprehensive. Moreover, materials relating to a given issue may be found in more than one location. For example, generic safety issues are defined as industry-wide problems inherent in nuclear plant design or operation (rather than deficiencies of individual manufacturers or managing utilities), and are organized in the NUCLEAR SAFETY AND RESEARCH series. However, generic problems manifest themselves in real incidents at individual reactor sites, so additional information may be found in the REACTOR SITES series.
The types of material in this collection remain fairly constant from series to series: primarily memoranda, reports, press releases, administrative law documents, speech and hearing transcripts and letters, with some printed articles, clippings and other miscellany. These materials have been organized to provide both subject access and insight into the functioning of the NRC. Thus, most of the series are organized first by subject, then chronologically, approximating the manner in which they were originally filed. In some cases, however, materials which were assembled for a specific purpose, such as research material, are left together, regardless of chronology.
Series Description
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS FILE, 1967-1984. (Boxes 1-5)
  Drafts and printed copies of speeches and writings by Victor Gilinsky relating to a wide range of subjects. Arranged chronologically.
- PERSONAL NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION OFFICE FILES, 1974-1984. (Boxes 6-24)
  Predominantly correspondence and miscellaneous administrative material. Arranged by form. It should be noted that the correspondence in this series includes many of the same correspondents in both the alphabetical and chronological sections.
- GENERAL NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION OFFICE FILES, 1972-1984. (Boxes 25-160)
  Memoranda, reports, hearing transcripts, letters and miscellany relating to internal administrative functions, budgets and pending issues. Arranged by form. The material generated by the NRC Office of the Secretary, consisting of reports, memoranda and other material related to NRC deliberations, has been organized according to the numerical order originally established. Material in other series often contains references to relevant documents in the SECY Papers.
- DOMESTIC NUCLEAR REACTOR LICENSING AND REGULATION, 1971-1984. (Boxes 161-187)
  Memoranda, reports, letters, clippings, printed articles, hearing transcripts, speech transcripts and miscellany relating to the licensing of nuclear reactors in the United States. A large amount of this material relates to controversies over delays and legislative attempts to reform the licensing process. Arranged by subject, and thereunder by date.
- INTERNATIONAL REGULATION AND EXPORT LICENSING, 1946-1984. (Boxes 188-233)
  Memoranda, reports, letters, clippings, printed articles, hearing transcripts and speech transcripts relating to non-proliferation issues generally, and specifically to the export of fuel and reactor components to individual countries. A significant amount of the material relates to the controversy surrounding exports to India. Arranged by country.
- NUCLEAR REACTOR OPERATION, 1974-1984. (Boxes 234-294)
  Memoranda, reports, letters, clippings, printed articles, hearing transcripts and speech transcripts relating to nuclear reactor construction and operation. Much of the material relates to waste management issues, particularly storage and non-proliferation concerns. Arranged by subject.
- NUCLEAR REACTOR SAFETY AND RESEARCH, 1957-1984. (Boxes 295-339)
  Reports, memoranda, clippings, printed articles, speech transcripts, letters, diagrams and other miscellany. Relates to emergency planning, reactor facility security, health and environmental issues, and generic safety problems. Arranged by subject.
- REACTOR SITES, 1974-1984. (Boxes 340-483)
  Clippings, printed articles, reports, letters, memoranda, hearing and speech transcripts relating to individual nuclear reactors in the United States. The material is arranged alphabetically by site and thereunder chronologically.
- GENERAL THREE MILE ISLAND INVESTIGATIONS, 1979-1984. (Boxes 484-531)
  Reports, hearing transcripts, telephone logs, trial materials, press releases, speech transcripts, clippings, printed articles, memoranda, and letters, relating to the accident at Three Mile Island (TMI), Pennsylvania, 1979 March-April. Arranged alphabetically by originating agency.
- NRC THREE MILE ISLAND INVESTIGATIONS, 1973-1984. (Boxes 532-628)
  Memoranda, reports, hearing transcripts, speech transcripts, press releases, clippings, printed articles, letters, and operator examinations. Arranged alphabetically by subject.
- SUBJECT FILE, 1943-1984. (Boxes 628-632)
  Speech transcripts, memoranda, letters, reports, press releases, printed articles and clippings predominantly relating to the economics of nuclear power, energy projections, the nuclear policies of Presidents Ford, Carter and Reagan, nuclear weapons, and other miscellaneous subjects. Arranged by subject.
- OVERSIZE FILE, 1981-1983. (Box 633)
  Computer printouts, a report, a resolution by the Pennsylvania State Senate, a map, and versions of a chart.
- PHOTOGRAPHS. (10.A-V)
  See photo card catalog for description.
Container List
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1967-1984
  - General. Miscellaneous speech materials, 1975 May-1979 June (Box 1., Folder 1)
  - The Japanese Civilian Nuclear Program, 1967 Aug. (with Paul Langer) Includes related materials (Folder 2)
  - The Possibility of Uranium Enrichment in Japan, 1969 June (Folder 3)
  - "A Missing Element in U.S. Antiproliferation Policy," 1970 June (with W. Hoehn)
  - Remarks, State/NRC Power Plant Siting Conference, 1975 April 7 (Folder 4)
  - "Safeguarding Nuclear Materials," 1975 May 2. Testimony, House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs, Subcommittee on Energy and the Environment (Morris Udall, Chairman; hereafter referred to as the Udall Committee) (Folder 6)
  - "Perspectives on Nuclear Regulation," 1975 June 4 (Folder 7)
  - "NRC Safeguards and Related Issues," 1975 June 18 (Folder 8)
  - "Nuclear Export Licensing and Related Issues," 1975 July 22. Testimony, Udall Committee (Folder 9)
  - "The Commission's Security Agency Study," 1975 Sept. 8 (Folder 10)
  - Remarks, Western Interstate Nuclear Board Meeting, 1975 Sept. 29 (Folder 11)
  - Remarks, Agreement States Meeting, 1975 Oct. 7 (Folder 12)
  - "The NRC and U.S. Nuclear Exports," 1975 Oct. 29 (Folder 13)
  - "U.S. Nuclear Exports and the Common Defense and Security," 1975 Nov. 15 (Folder 14)
  - "Plutonium: Deciding What to Do With It," 1975 Dec. 12 (Folder 15)
  - Testimony, Senate Committee on Government Operations, Subcommittee on Energy, Nuclear Proliferation and Government Processes (John Glenn, Chairman until 1981, followed by Charles Percy and Thad Cochran; hereafter referred to as the Glenn/Percy Committee), 1976 Jan. 29. Relates to exports (Folder 16)
  - "Nuclear Safety Policies: Present Practices," 1976 March (Folder 17)
  - "Nuclear Export Safeguards," 1976 March 9 (Folder 18)
  - "Safeguarding the Fuel Cycle," 1976 April 12 (Folder 19)
  - "Effective International Safeguards," 1976 June 7. Testimony, House Committee on International Relations, Subcommittee on International Security and Scientific Affairs (Clement Zablocki, Chairman; hereafter referred to as the Zablocki Committee) (Folder 20)
  - Decision, relating to ASCO II (Spain) reactor export, 1976 June 21 (Folder 21)
  - Remarks, Joint Committee on Atomic Energy (JCAE), 1976 June 22 (Folder 22)
  - Memorandum and order, relating to Tarapur (India) export, 1976 July 1 (Folder 23)
  - "Nuclear Reactor Safety and Federal Regulation," 1976 Oct. 7. Includes related materials (Folder 24)
  - "Plutonium, Proliferation and Policy," 1976 Nov. 1 and Nov. 10 (speech) and 1977 Feb. (article in Technology Review) (Box 2., Folder 1)
  - Remarks, Panel on the Spread of Nuclear Weapons, Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars, 1976 Dec. 9 (Folder 2)
  - Testimony, California Energy Resources Conservation and Development Commission, 1977 Jan. 31 (Folder 3)
  - "A U.S. View of Nuclear Energy at the Crossroads," 1977 March 9 (Folder 4)
  - Memorandum and order, relating to Tarapur (India) export, 1977 June 28 (Folder 5)
  - "Toward a Stricter International Discipline over the Uses of Nuclear Energy," 1977 July 25 (Folder 6)
  - "Nuclear Safety and Independent Regulation," 1977 Aug. (Folder 7)
  - Testimony, Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, Subcommittee on Energy Research and Development (Frank Church, Chairman until 1981, followed by Pete V. Domenici; hereafter referred to as the Church/Domenici Committee), 1977 Sept. 14. Relates to S. 897 (Folder 8)
  - "Anti-Proliferation: Rewriting the Rules," 1977 Sept. 26. Editorial sent to the Los Angeles Times (Folder 9)
  - "Nuclear Energy and Nuclear Proliferation," 1977 Nov. 3 (Folder 10)
  - "Some Thoughts on Nuclear Power Plant Standardization," 1977 Nov. 17 (Folder 11)
  - "The NRC's Valid Role in Nuclear Exports," Washington Post, 1978 Jan. 26 (Folder 12)
  - Testimony, Senate Committee on Environment and Public Works, Subcommittee on Nuclear Regulation (Gary Hart, Chairman until 1981, followed by Alan K. Simpson; hereafter referred to as the Hart/Simpson Committee), 1978 March 22. Relates to nuclear waste material (Folder 13)
  - Testimony, Glenn/Percy Committee, 1978 March 23. Relates to terrorism (Folder 14)
  - "NRC Regulation of the Uranium Milling Industry: Problems and Prospects," 1978 May 2 (Folder 15)
  - Testimony, Hart/Simpson Committee, 1978 June 14. Relates to nuclear waste material (Folder 16)
  - Testimony, House Committee on Interstate and Foreign Commerce, Subcommittee on Energy and Power (John Dingell, Chairman; hereafter referred to as the Dingell Committee). NOTE: This committee was apparently reorganized ca. 1980-1981 as the House Committee on Energy and Commerce, John Dingell, Chairman, Subcommittee on Energy Conservation and Power (Richard L. Ottinger, Chairman until 1984, followed by Edward J. Markey; hereafter referred to as the Ottinger/Markey Committee), 1978 July 20. Relates to licensing reform (Folder 17)
  - Testimony, Glenn/Percy Committee, 1978 July 26. Relates to nuclear waste (Folder 18)
  - "Taking Charge of Reactor Licensing," 1978 Sept. 11 (Folder 19)
  - "Plutonium, Proliferation and the Price of Money," 1978 Sept. 27 (speech), printed in Foreign Affairs, Winter, 1978-1979 (Folder 20-22)
  - Testimony, House Committee on Foreign Affairs, Subcommittee on International Economic Policy and Trade (Jonathan B. Bingham, Chairman until 1982, followed by Don Bonker; hereafter referred to as the Bingham/Bonker Committee), 1978 Oct. 3. Relates to exports (Box 3., Folder 1)
  - "Activating the Nuclear Regulatory Commission," 1979 Jan. 16 (Folder 2)
  - Testimony, Udall Committee, 1979 March 19. Relates to the shutdown of five plants for seismic re-evaluation (Folder 3)
  - Speech to Chinese nuclear delegation, 1979 March 27 (Folder 4)
  - "How Much Safety? At What Price?" 1979 May 30 (Folder 5)
  - Testimony, Committee on Environment and Public Works, 1979 June 14. Gilinsky renomination hearings (Folder 6)
  - Testimony, Udall Committee, 1979 July 19. Relates to the Agreement States program (Folder 7)
  - "Nuclear Energy and Three Mile Island," 1979 Sept. 19 (Folder 8)
  - "Some Thoughts on the Prospects for Nuclear Power: Electrical Demand and Nuclear Safety," 1979 Oct. 18 (Folder 9)
  - "The Effect of Three Mile Island on America's Nuclear Policy," 1979 Oct. 22 (Folder 10)
  - "Nuclear Reactor Regulation After Three Mile Island: What is Happening and What does it Mean?" 1979 Nov. 15 (Folder 11)
  - "'Delay', Public Participation and Public Confidence," 1979 Nov. 30 (Folder 12)
  - "The Impact of Three Mile Island," Bulletin of the Atomic Scientist, 1980 Jan. (Folder 13)
  - "U.S.-Indian Nuclear Relations," 1980 Feb. 5. Includes related materials (Folder 14)
  - "Three Mile Island Plus One," 1980 March 25. Includes related materials (Folder 15)
  - "One-Man Rule Over Nuclear Safety," Washington Post, 1980 April 7. Includes related materials (Folder 16)
  - Testimony, Glenn/Percy Committee, 1980 April 18. Relates to NRC reorganization plans (Folder 17-18)
  - Testimony, House Committee on Government Operations, Subcommittee on Energy and Natural Resources (Anthony Toby Moffett, Chairman until 1982, followed by Mike Synar; hereafter referred to as the Moffett Committee), 1980 May 6. Relates to NRC reorganization plans (Folder 19)
  - "Nuclear Energy: Electricity, Safety, and Indian Point," 1980 May 15 (Folder 20)
  - Statement, Virginia Bar Association Annual Convention, 1980 June 20. Includes related materials (Folder 21)
  - "Nuclear Energy: Electricity and Safety," 1980 Sept. 23 (Box 4., Folder 1)
  - "Nuclear Reactors and Nuclear Bombs," 1980 Nov. 17 (Folder 2)
  - "Hydrogen Control and Reactor Containments," 1981 March 13. Includes related materials (Folder 3-4)
  - "Nuclear Power: Safety and Self-Interest," 1981 April 9. Includes related materials (Folder 5)
  - Letter to the editor, Philadelphia Inquirer, 1981 May 12 (Folder 6)
  - "The New Policy for Nuclear Power," 1981 Oct. 27 (Folder 7)
  - "Nuclear Regulation: Who Needs It?" 1981 Nov. 5 (Folder 8)
  - Testimony, Senate Committee on Foreign Affairs, 1981 Dec. 2. Relates to International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) safeguards (Folder 9)
  - Statement, Symposium on Nuclear Proliferation, 1981 Dec. 11 (Folder 10)
  - "Keeping More Countries from Getting Nuclear Weapons," 1982 Jan. 19 (Folder 11)
  - Statement, Bankers Trust Company Meeting, 1982 Jan. 21 (Folder 12)
  - "Future of Nuclear Power," 1982 Feb. 10 (Folder 13)
  - "Full Ahead for Nuclear Power?" Technology Review, 1982 Feb.-March (Folder 14)
  - "Can We Safeguard the Nuclear Fuel Cycle?" 1982 April 12 (Folder 15)
  - "Nuclear Issues and Trends," 1982 April 23 (Folder 16)
  - "Streamlining Nuclear Regulation?" 1982 May 24 (Folder 17)
  - "Issues Before the NRC," 1982 May 27 (Folder 18)
  - "Nuclear Power and Nuclear Proliferation," 1982 July 13 (Folder 19)
  - "The Administration's Risky Plutonium Policy," Wall Street Journal, 1982 July 15 (Folder 20)
  - "Nuclear Power Safety--Lessons from U.S. Experience," 1982 July 31 (Folder 21)
  - "More Nuclear Weapon States?" 1982 Sept. 25 (Folder 22)
  - Testimony, Ottinger/Markey Committee, 1982 Oct. 1. Relates to Indian Point nuclear power station (Folder 23)
  - "What Are We Going to Do with Spent Fuel?" 1982 Oct. 13. Includes related materials (Folder 24)
  - "More Nuclear Weapon States?" 1982 Oct. 28 (Folder 25)
  - "U.S.-Indian Relations," 1982 Nov. 23 (Folder 26)
  - Interview, British Granada Television, 1982 Dec. 15 (Folder 27)
  - "Nuclear Energy: Issues and Trends," 1982 Dec. 10 (Folder 28)
  - "More Nuclear Weapons States?" 1983 Jan. 14. Modification of 1982 Oct. 28 speech (Folder 29)
  - "Nuclear Safety: Dealing with Conflicts of Interest," 1983 Jan. 27 (Folder 30)
  - "Thoughts on Forty Years of Researching and Developing the Application of Nuclear Energy," 1983 Feb. 1 (Folder 31)
  - "Nuclear Trouble Spots and What to Do About Them," 1983 Feb. 3 (Box 5., Folder 1)
  - "The First Step in Solving the Nuclear Waste Problem: Providing Adequate Spent Fuel Storage," 1983 Feb. 28 (Folder 2)
  - Review of M. Kaku and J. Trainer, Nuclear Power: Both Sides; The Best Arguments For and Against the Most Controversial Technology, in Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists, 1983 May (Folder 3)
  - Testimony, Hart/Simpson Committee, 1983 May 25. Relates to licensing reform (Folder 4)
  - "Nuclear Energy: Issues and Trends," 1983 June 8 (Folder 5)
  - Testimony, Udall Committee, 1983 June 9. Relates to licensing reform (Folder 6)
  - "Memorandum for the Parties in the Three Mile Island Unit I Proceeding," 1983 June 22 (Folder 7)
  - "Why Keep Helping India Make the Bomb?" Wall Street Journal, 1983 July 5. Includes related materials (Folder 8)
  - Letter to the Editor, Wall Street Journal, 1983 Aug. 18 (Folder 9)
  - Testimony, Ottinger/Markey Committee, 1983 Sept. 23. Relates to licensing reform (Folder 10)
  - "Facing the Realities of a Fragmented Nuclear Power Industry," 1983 Oct. 12. Includes related materials (Folder 11)
  - Testimony, Bingham/Bonker Committee, 1983 Oct. 26. Relates to the Nuclear Non-proliferation Treaty (Folder 12)
  - Speech, Bingham Conference, Columbia University, 1983 Oct. 31 (Folder 13)
  - "Restraining the Spread of Nuclear Weapons: A Walk on the Supply Side," 1983 Dec. 1 (Folder 14)
  - Testimony, Senate, hearings held by Senator Arlen Specter, 1983 Dec. 16. Relates to the re-start of TMI Unit 1 (Folder 15)
  - Testimony, Udall Committee, 1984 Jan. 24. Relates to Diablo Canyon (Folder 16)
  - Testimony, Udall Committee, 1984 Feb. 9. Relates to the NRC budget (Folder 17)
  - "Learning a Living," 1984 Feb. 9. Relates to operator training (Folder 18)
  - Testimony, Hart/Simpson Committee, 1984 Feb. 23. Relates to the NRC budget and licensing reform (Folder 19)
  - "Restraining the Spread of Nuclear Weapons--What Next?" 1984 March 1 and April 5 (Folder 20)
  - "Nuclear Waste: A New Approach," 1984 March 12 (Folder 21)
  - Testimony, Senate Committee on Appropriations, Subcommittee on Energy and Water Development (Mark Hatfield, Chairman; hereafter referred to as the Hatfield Committee), 1984 March 21. Relates to the NRC budget (Folder 22)
  - Testimony, House Committee on Appropriation, Subcommittee on Energy and Water Development (Thomas Bevill, Chairman; hereafter referred to as the Bevill Committee), 1984 March 22. Relates to the NRC budget (Folder 23)
  - "Additional Separate View of Commissioner Gilinsky on Reinstatement of Low-Power Operating License at Diablo Canyon," 1984 April 13 (Folder 24)
  - "U.S. Nuclear Power--Larger Operating Companies a Condition for Success," 1984 May 14 (Folder 25)
  - Testimony, Udall Committee, 1984 May 17. Relates to the Shoreham nuclear power plant (Folder 26)
  - "Reactor Safety--Need More Emphasis on Operation," 1984 June 6 (Folder 27)
  - "Too Many Nuclear Utilities," Wall Street Journal, 1984 June 18 (Folder 28)
  - Testimony, Ottinger/Markey Committee, 1984 June 21. General comments relating to the NRC (Folder 29)
- PERSONAL NUCLEAR REGULATORY COMMISSION OFFICE FILES, 1974-1984
  - General
    - Appointment books
      - 1975 (?)-1981 (Box 6., Folder 1-5)
      - 1982-1984 (Box 7., Folder 1-3)
    - Calendars, 1978-1984 (Folder 4-10)
    - Clippings relating to Dr. Gilinsky's tenure on the NRC, 1984 March-July (Folder 11)
    - Trip files. Miscellaneous material, 1977 Oct.-1984 Feb. (Box 8., Folder 1-7)
  - Correspondence. Alphabetical
    - Agnew, Harold, 1981-1983 (Folder 8)
    - Babbitt, Bruce, 1983. Correspondence and statements (Folder 9)
    - Bevill, Thomas (Rep.), 1980. Letter (Folder 10)
    - Bingham, Jonathan (Rep.), 1980. Letter (Folder 11)
    - Boggs, Lindy (Rep.), 1979. Letter (Folder 12)
    - Clark, Wilson, (Gov. Edmund Brown's office), 1979. Letter and speech transcript (Folder 13)
    - Cochran, Thomas (National Resources Defense Council), 1978 (Folder 14)
    - Cohen, Karl, 1978. Speech transcript and letter (Folder 15)
    - Corey, Gordon, (Commonwealth Edison), 1978-1981. Correspondence, speech transcripts, report (Folder 16)
    - Cronkite, Walter, 1980. Letter (Folder 17)
    - Cubie, James, 1981. Letter (Folder 18)
    - Dalton, John M., 1979. Letters, memoranda, charts, press release (Box 9., Folder 1)
    - Duchene, Francois, 1979. Letter (Folder 2)
    - Edwards, James E., 1981. Letter and clipping (Folder 3)
    - Findley, Paul (Rep.), 1980. Letter (Folder 4)
    - Gillberg, Bjorn O., 1977-1978. Letters, report and miscellany (Folder 5)
    - Gillette, Robert (Los Angeles Times), 1977. Letters and articles (Folder 6)
    - Glenn, John (Senator), 1980. Letter (Folder 7)
    - Hart, Gary (Senator), 1977-1980. Letters (Folder 8)